Get ready for Muppet domination.
The Muppets is a family, comedy, music film directed by James Bobin.
When Kermit the Frog and the Muppets learn that their beloved theater is slated for demolition, a sympathetic human, Gary, and his
puppet brother, Walter, swoop in to help the gang put on a show and raise the $10 million they need to save the day.
Gary, played by Jason Segel.
Mary, played by Amy Adams.
Tex Richman, played by Chris Cooper.
CDE Executive, played by Rashida Jones.
Kermit / Beaker / Statler / Rizzo / Link / Newsman
(voice), played by Steve Whitmire.
Walter (voice), played by Peter Linz.
The Muppets is a 2011 American musical comedy film directed by James Bobin (in his feature length
directorial debut) from a screenplay written by Jason Segel and Nicholas Stoller.
Produced by David Hoberman and Todd Lieberman, it is the
seventh theatrical film featuring the Muppets.
The film stars Segel, Amy Adams, Chris Cooper and Rashida Jones as well as Muppet performers Steve
Whitmire, Eric Jacobson, Dave Goelz, Bill Barretta, David Rudman, Matt Vogel and Peter Linz.
Bret McKenzie served as music supervisor, writing four of the film's five
original songs, while Christophe Beck composed the score.
In the film, devoted Muppet fan Walter, his human brother Gary and the latter's girlfriend Mary help Kermit the Frog reunite the disbanded
Muppets in order to save the Muppet Theater from Tex Richman, a greedy oil magnate who plots to drill for oil on its former site.
Walt Disney Pictures announced development of a seventh Muppet film in March 2008, with Segel and
Stoller as the screenwriters and Hoberman and Lieberman's Mandeville Films as co-producer.
Conceived to serve as a creative reboot for the franchise after years of being largely out of the public eye following Disney's acquisition of the Muppets in 2004, Segel
and Stoller intently addressed the Muppets' recent real-world lack of public exposure and fame in mainstream culture within the context of the film's story.
As a result, The Muppets became the first film in the series to directly acknowledge
The Muppet Show and reference plot points from previous Muppet films.
Bobin was hired to direct in January 2010, and the film's supporting cast was filled out
in October of the same year with the casting of Adams, Cooper and Jones.
Filming took place from September 2010 to February 2011.
The film was the first theatrical Muppets production to not star Frank Oz and Jerry Nelson performing
their respective characters, although Nelson contributes an uncredited voice cameo.
Instead, their roles are performed by Jacobson and Vogel, respectively,
marking their theatrical feature film debut as those characters.
The Muppets premiered at the Savannah Film Festival on November 4, 2011, and was released
theatrically in North America on November 23, by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
The film was a critical and commercial success; it received universal acclaim for its humor, music, and
revitalization of the Muppet characters, and grossed over $171 million worldwide on a budget of $45 million.
The film won the Academy Award for Best Original Song for McKenzie's song "Man or
Muppet", as well as earning BAFTA and Critic's Choice Awards nominations.
A sequel, titled Muppets Most Wanted, was released on March 21, 2014.
The film explores themes of musical, based on toy,
puppetry, hollywood, los angeles, california.
The tone is lighthearted.